Talk on the phone. Finish your homework. Watch TV. Die.
The House of the Devil is a horror, mystery film directed by Ti West.
A young college student who’s struggling financially takes a strange
babysitting job which coincides with a full lunar eclipse.
She slowly realizes her clients harbor a terrifying
secret, putting her life in mortal danger.
Samantha, played by Jocelin Donahue.
Mr. Ulman, played by Tom Noonan.
Mrs. Ulman, played by Mary Woronov.
Megan, played by Greta Gerwig.
Victor Ulman, played by AJ Bowen.
Landlady, played by Dee Wallace.
The House of the Devil is a 2009 American horror film written, directed, and edited by Ti
West, starring Jocelin Donahue, Tom Noonan, Mary Woronov, Greta Gerwig, A.
Bowen, and Dee Wallace.
The plot concerns a young college student who is hired as a babysitter at an isolated house and
is soon caught up in bizarre and dangerous events as she fights for her life.
The film combines elements of both the slasher film and haunted house subgenres
while using the "satanic panic" of the 1980s as a central plot element.
It pays homage to the style of horror films of the 1970s and 1980s by using
filmmaking techniques and technology commonly employed at the time.
The opening text claims that the film is based on true events, a practice used in horror films
such as The Texas Chain Saw Massacre (1974) and The Amityville Horror (1979).
The film explores themes of ritual, pentagram, cult, pizza, pay phone.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.